welcome to our Saturday morning session
we normally have a roundtable at this
time but today we are doing a solution
raising on media and how we get our
information so we it's an hour-long
conversation where we can generate
potential solutions for 10,000 people
and $100,000 we start with 15 minutes on
what we currently do in this space so
whoever wants to start what does your
information sources look like either for
you as an individual or what you think
society is doing good and bad and I can
start I don't have a drone that they
want to start because I don't take a
little bit more of a backseat to listen
Daniel do you want to start yes because
I don't have I still don't think I have
a lot to say on this subject um I get a
ton of information from YouTube I get I
think that's the majority of the way I
spend my my information gathering
podcasts on YouTube essentially um you
know if I want to dig deeper I'll go to
Wikipedia
I'll check some of the you know some
news sites BBC USA Today CNN al-jazeera
sometimes just to see if I'm you know
missing something important like
breaking news wise um but that's
definitely secondary from getting
information from podcasts on YouTube and
then it shows like John Oliver I'll
watch that and I think that's do you
know and then I'm on Facebook a bit too
so what people are throwing around there
try not to do um the echo chamber thing
you know people I like the fact that I
do have a variety of friends and that's
a good thing um that's my current
situation that's what I currently
observe going on in my life I haven't
thought enough about it to know how it
what I would do to make it different
there was the one the Wikipedia folks
started that network for what is it
called
that's the Wikipedia News Network and
you can create an account and you can
post news stories but you can edit the
title so you make the title of the news
story more accurate so if you are on
that social network and all it is is
news and you're scrolling through news
stories and it's another categorized and
you can dig into like the topics that
you want to follow but if I post a news
story on there I have the ability to
just totally change the title to make it
more accurate but it's Wikipedia so if I
post if someone else can change it you
know and it's supposed to hone in on the
truth I can't remember the name of it
I'll look it up right now and I think
that's all I got I can go next I've
never heard of that before
I've definitely heard of Wikipedia so
I'll look right now here yeah for me I
get less about my news sources I get
less news sources so kind of just have
put up blinders to what's currently
going on because I feel like there's
only so much I can take in but I watched
a long Krissy now I also watch I was
easier and I sometimes watch The Young
Turks as well as just the comedy ones I
like to get my news through comedy it's
like the Saturday morning or Saturday
Night Live's Weekend Update and Trevor
Noah and all the people in that realm
the issue is a lot of what we're
tackling it like there's a lot of
misinformation it's a news story that's
designed for entertainment instead of
for information and they have to read
like if you're talking about let's say
war in the Middle East well you can't
give the whole background every time and
you so it's like you can't really say
why it's happening all you can do is you
don't even necessarily know accurately
if it's something happened and then why
it happens and like there's no way to
get the background information it's just
basically a new
speed of stories like right now drink
opiate nineteen everything seems to be
about Co but nineteen it's like okay I
get it I was attached at the news for
the first week but what story are you
gonna tell like what it's 24/7 so then
they have to sensationalize everything
and so that people are here instead of
on your channel for coca nineteen and
there's a big problem that we get our
entertainment from our news and so it's
sensationalization and then the changing
about the title a bright for clickbait
when it's not like there was just one
for koban nineteen of like Oh baby dies
in South Africa well no that's not what
happens someone had cope in nineteen
gave birth and the baby died did they
die from Cove in nineteen they had it
but they were also premature and had
lung issues and like you know like
there's just but the article was
definitely misleading and so a lot of
misinformation and you're Gerald Bentley
would you like to say what you said oh
you're working in this realm so why why
yeah well as far as my personal
information diet it is mostly YouTube
right now I got some youtubers that I
follow mostly science space and then
some dealing with software development
which is the area I'm in and then some
for entertainment and some that do like
Lego buildings and more you know more
you know entertainment I'm on Facebook
although I just realized I missed
several large news stories because I
blocked everyone who not blocked I just
unfollowed everyone who tends to be low
quality information sources and
apparently that was most everyone so so
I'm actually I'm kind of way out of the
loop lots of stuff but yeah I used to
watch the television news but then it's
it's mostly just kind of a daily death
count and then here's to a good
feel-good stories and then here's some
some news that has no real impact on to
my life it's just the most entertaining
- for people to watch as opposed to
actually informative and I haven't
really found a solution for that
although I guess really looking at it
I'm not sure that there's a lot of
information going on in the world
that that is important I mean what's
what's really important to me is is you
know what's happening in the industry I
work in and in the areas that I have
interest so like regular news is not
important it's good to know what your
government is up to so it'd be it'd be
nice if I had a reliable source of that
but you know every news source you go to
is is coming from a slant and I just
don't have the time or the energy to to
disambiguate where they're slanting
where they're inaccurate and where
they're doing all that all on my own but
I haven't Roy I haven't really curated
that that news those news sources yet to
make sure I hon things in the digital
world in the in my industry it's much
easier so I've kind of curated there
yeah and then so yeah I'd like to you
know I started my project reason score
because there is such it's so hard to
determine the actual quality of the
maybe the way to say it is that the
proximity of that information to actual
reality is something that's hard to
determine so I decided I wanted to make
that easier and you know almost ten
years later I meant further on it I
don't want to dive in too much of that
unless it comes up in the conversation
naturally so yeah so I've pretty much
blocked everything out I mean I'm on
Twitter and Facebook but those are very
curated feeds of mostly my industry and
stuff and then a couple of people that I
follow and still like you know good half
the content I don't care about I mean it
would be nice I guess we'll get into
this later but it'd be nice to have more
control over what I see so yeah so we'll
get into that later part of it but
that's that's pretty much me so yeah
I guess I'll go quick I just kind of
like you guys I try to check out a
variety of different media types so I do
watch some mainstream news and I'll go
to Democracy Now and a lot of YouTube
just really trying to make my own
choices and look at each one from their
angle and be like okay they're trying to
push something how do I feel about it
just kind of neutralize what I'm seeing
is I can go next
so for actually watching the news I
don't watch the news for news purposes
all that much anymore mostly because I
don't trust almost anyone I tend to
watch it kind of as a spectator I
intentionally did not unfollow or
unfriend all the people posting that
stuff on Facebook I like to see what
they post and I had to see well you know
how people counter it I also like to see
what people on the opposite end of the
spectrum post and how different those
two things are and then when I attend it
to to dig deep is when there's something
especially interesting like the two
groups just really don't agree on some
key information and then they go and
poke around and see like what it
actually seems is it is going on a lot
of the times it's incredibly difficult
to find information that I'm like oh I
that seems trustworthy
I now have made a choice on what's good
good good going on that is incredibly
rare but yeah that I tend to like the
comedy news sources that type of thing
still take those with a grain of salt
too because it's still often try to push
a narrative but still funny too should
you want to share what you do for news
or what you think is good and bad about
the space right now well there's a lot
of bad things about the news right now
sorry information and I found
all babies interrupting zooms and
streams since well long before they
existed I can do a second thoughts
something else came to mind that I
noticed so as someone that doesn't work
in journalism you know I think we do
need journalism you know I have no
background in that but I know well it
seems it appears that that industry is
just struggling as a whole like that's
why I like the long-form YouTube things
where it seems like you know people can
really share nuanced opinions and and
whatnot what sometimes I guess baffles
me is some folks will post articles I
see on my social media to sites that
have subscriber paywalls and I can read
like the first two paragraphs and then
I'm just left with this feeling like
gosh if this is important information
like people should be able to know about
it and I you know but if people are
providing a good service
she knows should they be compensated
yeah I don't know how to solve that
problem but sometimes I'm like you know
I'll see something that looks really
important and I'm like should I be
paying $5.99 a month for this I I don't
know like I don't know how to value it
but if this is important for being on
planet Earth
why are we pay walling important
information I have no clue that's just
something else I notice yeah I think
that's a really important point I think
all of the the the trust issues are just
not all of them but a great number of
the ones that came to light we're just
because as a society we decided that we
didn't need to pay for news anymore we
don't need you know newspapers it's
online it it's free forever now I'm
never paying for foreigners again is not
everyone's but I think enough people
standpoint that then news organizations
had to scramble to figure out how do we
stay in business and some
didn't and then some did but they either
had to you know go sketchy with
clickbait headlines and heavy
advertising or they had to sell you know
to Jeff Bezos or or somebody who now
owns a bunch of different news
organizations and we're starting to see
that same poll you know of just like the
government legislation and things sort
of skewing it in a favor the ones that
own the media surprisingly enough have
the media skewed in that favor yeah I do
like some of the solutions that people
are working on in that space that
haven't caught on like you know
microtransactions so maybe I'm not
paying $5.99 a month which anyways that
you know if I read an article then I
don't you know charge like three or four
cents or something like that to my
account I would love something like that
yeah so there's been and so that's meant
to be across like all the different news
agencies so indicates a daniels say he
goes to read a page he gets halfway
through it and it pay well blocks him
instead he might pay a couple of dollars
a month in each article he reads as soon
as he goes there it's like oh that
writer get hot ends yeah I've heard of
something I guess is referred to as
tipping and that I mean we need a
language for this I'm not sure that's it
but it's like yeah you can write it up
you read articles since you've logged in
with your account you know by the end of
it it's you click a button and yet it
sends two cents or four cents whatever
to that author yeah there's a couple of
things the the problem is getting enough
organizations to take it on that it's
that it's a consistent enough
environment so nothing's caught on
there's like buy me a coffee and there's
several tipping things and then also you
have transaction costs so you have to
check out a way to handle reduce the
transaction costs where you can do it in
fraction you know in pennies because the
credit card transactions twenty-five
cent charge minimum twenty five to
thirty I know we didn't fully tackle
what is currently happy in the
information space over at the fifteen
minute
so now we can move on to what we would
like to see in this space so in our
perfect version of a world how are you
getting news how is the world getting
news they don't need to match one
another's you can give your vision you
can even contradict yourself I'm sure I
will so anyone who would like to share
that sure closer
I wanted two of the things is on the
funding one of the big things that I
think they do in the UK is with our TV
licences and then a lot or possibly all
of that money goes to the BBC and so
that ends up being a form of income
that's reliable that from what I can
tell isn't as dependent on like the
government being happy with you
which is one of the things that's really
dangerous like in Canada where we have
the CBC but the government can control
how much money we actually give them and
so if it's an organization so if the
government maybe doesn't like what the
news is saying about them they can then
start to cut funding which kind of
defeats the purpose and a lot of the
case so something similar to - to the
BBC where it's tax basically but it's
not through the government as far as
words like if they wanted to change the
tax or who it goes to
they would probably in being like an
election where were saying hey how much
did do the people think that these news
organizations should get who should get
it and the government can't just touch
anything to do with that tax without
massive public approval yeah
or redone there Adrian oh yeah yeah I do
have kind of concerns about that but I
don't have a better solution what I
would like to see is is being able to
subscribe to specific topics and be able
to filter my news so I'd like to be able
to ask an AI or I mean I'm concerned
about black box a eyes but something
where you can you can set up rules on on
what content you want to receive but
then I also you know if someone's
posting an article ideally all of the
source content should be available like
if they talked on the phone or send an
email to that person why are those
recordings
fully available right they you don't
have to read it in the article but give
me a link to go to that source stuff so
just some general kind of guidance on
how journalism happens in a world where
actual storing of content is not the
expensive thing the expensive thing as
the attention in the quality of time and
then yeah some sort of kind of better
feedback mechanism than comments and
stuff so that as the information changes
or as you can get more input because I
think a lot of time the reason why we
have such a divisive environment is that
the content that's created is slanted
and there's no way to make sure that the
knowledge of the other group is in there
and not that I think everything needs to
be like completely balanced between the
two sides but if we can fully represent
the intent of both sides then I think
that that news could be trusted much
better because you can see everything
but then of course it's a lot of data
and you have to figure out how summarize
it which is part of what I'm working on
so yeah so being able to control what
content I see to better extent having it
be able to go as deep as I want into
that content rather than have it having
just the final published product and
then kind of a feedback mechanism so it
grows and improves would be something
unlike having a medium grade I I would
be very useful something like in science
fiction literature II you can have
something called a butler which it's
like add you know in your background
just sifting through the news and
presenting you with relevant data and
also able to get both points of view
like for every fact you have you can
have multiple views on we know what
happened like the president said this
and this but then interpretations there
are lots of and left side right side
they all have the same
they have the same fact but they
interpreted in totally different way so
what I found useful also basically for
each piece of news to read the extreme
left and well maybe not extreme because
extreme is not very useful but left and
right sources and that interpretation
and then interpolate from that more or
less mmm I know what happened but I then
know why something happened and I
usually can see how it is connected so
like everything else so yeah so
something that could do it for me would
be very useful because of these days it
seems there is no unbiased source of
information anymore if you already
looked at like all sides calm or there's
I think there's two or three projects
that try and give you a single article
written by multiple or single topic
covered by multiple news sources that
pretty cool all sides calm I think it's
like when I'll put it in the description
for the YouTube one after if there's
also the one that Daniel had suggested
that WT social wiki tribunal social that
we have talked about for a beginning
section theoretically that's what we
talked about in getting section we also
say what's working what's beautiful then
we can link to although this to be like
here's what's cool and happening but we
haven't necessarily but actually do you
know I can't see who's immune it or not
but if anyone else would like to share
so if I could dream big just took a
couple notes here so I wish that news
was just more straightforward more to
the point you know where the the most
relevant information was right at the
top and then you know as the story
expands and there's more detail it's
further down I
I think my experiences it's not quite
like that I should get the meet the most
important part of the story in the first
couple sentences and then you know I
don't think I'm seeing that um news
that's more straightforward I wish I
could trust the headlines we mentioned
that a little bit but gosh how many
times I read a story and I'm like this
isn't what the headline was saying um
it's weird um I wish that there was more
emphasis on I guess just better topics
emphasis on technology news that and
health news
so when people felt like they went to
whatever website or thing they're
reading I mean we're not the news seems
so much about like personalities and and
just stories that aren't like helpful to
my to my well-being
um I don't know how else to put it
I wish that there were stories that
showcased good role models and people
that and role models like that you know
we're kind of achievable in life like
wow look at this person and how they got
their life together or something like I
mean that would be cool you know you can
find those but they're just not in the
main things I wish that journal at
journalism wasn't like pandering to
political parties or corporations there
are some stories that like if you know
what you're looking for they're kind of
like an ad but it's you know cloaked as
a news story so that's a wish I wish
that I guess finally that it wasn't we
had news there are real things to fear
in the world but I wish that it wasn't
playing to people's
years so hugely and like there are
terrible stories but I think right
Daniel I'm just gonna do you have one
more point you would like in the future
before and then I just wanted three of
us haven't shared yet so Shiloh and Ralf
would you like to just share Thank You
Daniel hmm hope to say quickly um I'd
like to see more like I'm a half hour
away from the state capital in
Washington here but I'd like to see more
of my local community news like I don't
we don't have any way to totally connect
but there's thousands of people here and
I'm sure there's news I mean there are
like neighborhood different with you
know whatever but it's not it's very
random and rare so it'd be kind of cool
just to see the positive stuff is going
on in your community
not quite sure so I think building a bit
on what Bentley talked about with the
like you know seeing a heavy emphasis on
the underlying source also understanding
through all the different channels
involved who the experts are that are
being touted as we see like for example
with all kovat 19 thing oh we brought on
a doctor to say this keep it a doctor of
what doctor philosophy I don't care what
that person has to say about the virus I
mean I do but don't tell me that it did
or doctor because that's not the you
know that that's not the implication
that they're using is that the person
has you know a doctorate of something if
the news says it that the person is a
doctor that means something to people
and I feel that there's a lot of that
going on and that's a sort of a
cornerstone of the misinformation thing
is people kind of now know we can't
trust our governments we can't trust
news I think overall we know that we can
trust some experts but now we don't know
which ones and they're all being touted
with the same like oh this person is
great they're smart you can totally
trust what they're saying and then they
contradict each other and so then we
have to figure out okay so now it's not
even figuring out the source because
this person has a bunch of history and
probably a ton of sources that they've
reviewed how do I tell them apart I will
try to quickly share mine there's a lot
of background I think we need before the
actual that isn't just information like
tools that help us assess and understand
science because unfortunately the media
is where we get our science from as well
as history to be able to zoom in and out
of history and truly understand it and
understand the complexities of it I
think would really help with news in
particular that being said for news I
want it broken down into what is
happening what actually is happening
what how do I know that that happened
how do I trust it why did it happen
which I can go do from the history and
also what does it mean for the future
why does this matter right like so
that's gonna be speculation and it's
gonna be very premature and kind of like
arbitrary it's gonna differ between
person but the facts shouldn't and so
like what happened can we could have
different opinions but the actual facts
should be the same
but even just having one place to see
that it's it's more great area to have
it broken down into who was involved how
do we know they were involved what
happened
having multiple sources of photographers
and journalism are you having like what
is a journalist I guess it's a big
because if we're all have phones are we
all journalists because journalists are
either reporting the facts so they're
giving you the commentary if it's the
commentary I I do want journalists who
can tell me the story in a way that's
going to be somewhat entertaining and
it's Moorea I'm going to get that
information and so what does that look
like and how do they get paid for it
without breaking news and itself because
if I'm gonna get paid for interesting
then I'm gonna pick the most interesting
stories I'm gonna sensationalize them
I'm gonna click baby titles on them so
that I can get my 5 cents per Journal
article so I want to have it broken down
to who what when where why how and be
able to like truly see what parts are
black and white and what parts are more
gray and and change and be able to see
what went into this event happening
without them needing to give me that
every every time a news story starts so
we have about a minute and a half left
if anyone else wants to give any photo
cuts for this section before we move on
to the adjacent possible I was just
thinking and I don't know if this fits
in that section or this section but
maybe he hit news jury where you
randomly selects 20 people to look at a
news article they raid it and then that
determines whether they see it where
rather than the Clickbank titles and
some of the other stuff and maybe have
them tag it as well
Jeff ante of having a pool of money like
where we like the CBC but instead of the
government saying yes this is we can
take or give you're funny and having the
funding and then having the Canadian
citizens in this case the CBC say what
do we want to know and also being able
to say how much of my local news I want
and how much global news I want right
there's things that happen all over the
world I'm like why don't I know about
that that's much bigger story than was
happy in America right now which is like
yeah so I'm like instead of a liquid
democracy a liquid news organization
yeah
so like you know if you think how to get
that five dollars a month towards news
and you can say okay I want to of that
federally to provincial II in one
locally and then I can pick the news
outlets and that then that kind of
becomes almost like a patreon where that
person says oh I've got you know a
million subscribers each paying me three
dollars a month alright I've got 30
million a month to truly not to play
with Danny you want to give it a quick
thought before I was kinda like that's a
perfect rendering idea one other idea
come now if this already exists then
like one second Daniel sorry because if
we are switching over to the next topic
which that'll be perfect for which is
maybe not because maybe it's too much
money in which case I'll let you still
say it but so now we're talking about
what we could actually create right now
if we had ten thousand people and a
hundred thousand dollars and it sounds
like that might be in what you're saying
so go what would you what was the keys
what if this could already exist I mean
what if you had a way to have a site
that stories were voted up by
significance or something should have
like maybe like a crowd-sourced so that
because right now as we have it the the
companies that are controlling the
narratives they decide always what's at
the top right so yeah I think that's
read it but sure I do like the idea of
having the relevance be so I vote right
ice meat something I say oh my god yes
everyone needs to but it doesn't
necessarily say everyone needs to they
look at it and say oh you're Vancouver
right of course you think everyone needs
to know this and it's that would send
the vancouver stories the vancouver
people right or it upload those and it's
like oh you're queer ya know but you
wonder you want to watch that you don't
I mean like it takes my demographics
into account and then helps me vote in
that way so that I can say yes this is
relevant everyone needs to know this is
going on but it kind of only goes to the
relevant people of like you know like
when Daniel mentioned technology
everyone needs to know what technology I
want to know about technology I know a
ton of people don't care at all right so
like for me to say everyone needs to
know this is what's happening an apple
probably isn't gonna but there's like an
AI that could help us
I think for that I think you vote on the
category like how important is this
thing to that category so is this
super-important for technology great if
I don't care about technology still
don't show me but like if it's you know
low importance for technology and
business the high importance for the
environment then that can start to show
you or start to control who it's shown
to if other people who also liked the
environment said hey dude this is
important for the environment it's not
saying you know that you're gonna agree
that or what it's just saying it's an
important topic to to discuss as far as
that top goes yeah and I think that's
kind of how red it ended up working
today because you subscribe to specific
channels so they're both right up in the
channels so it's not presented that way
but I think has a similar net result
which I think that still has the
challenge with the clickbait tier titles
tend to get clicked up and that's why
kind of the journey method is a way of
taking that out you don't as like being
a member of the network you agree that
you're gonna review five articles week
or some X number of articles for a
period of time and rate it yeah I think
on that mixed with the jury I think you
also have sort of like fake articles
that aren't published and I'm not sure
if there's like template articles where
you can just plug in you know it's like
a news madlibs where it's just sort of
like you know name verb that or not it
uh or if it actually takes an existing
article and just says okay we're gonna
make a couple of tweaks and you know
change Trump to Hillary and change a
couple of things and just see how you're
voting might change see if you you know
think well now it's absolutely true you
just said it was fake for the other
person to do something like that so that
you have a jury but it's also using that
information from when they were given
like a what do you think about this
article oh you think that's terrible
okay it's not true and you just said it
was fine five minutes to go for it yeah
do that first yeah they have some sort
of bias detection by by rating the
individual person's ability to be
unbiased that's interesting
so if we wanted to I mean is that kind
of where we're going to think for the
ten people and the money or does anyone
have another suggestion don't need to
have one particular it's just like
anything that is like is that possible
for a hundred thousand dollars and ten
thousand people I don't know you guys
are tech to know more about the the the
finances so I don't think so
like what could we solve for news with
ten thousand people right maybe let me
know I could build that in a weekend it
wouldn't look good and if you had ten
dozen people willing to try it yeah
but but yeah I don't want to stop their
ideas the jury thing you're talking
about bid their you could build in a
weekend yeah it's it's it would just be
reddit with an additional piece that it
chooses you know five random people for
an article that comes in and has them
review it before it shows it to the
community so people would still well I
mean that you wouldn't be able to make
your own news company but you could have
a tour people could post articles to it
that they see and then it puts it
through the round jury and then it and
then it spits it out on the on the home
page and then has tagging so yeah I
think I think that could be I mean I
think there ends up being like this is a
really difficult thing and I think this
is where Billy and I are trying to like
all right don't talk the entire time
because he and I probably both could
there's a bunch of different sort of
prongs on attack but I think you need to
do to actually get it and like I think
part of it is you have to be able to
tackle the expert thing because if you
have experts giving their feedback um
you know this and the article and it's
an that well why should we trust that
person and then the evidence that's
being dissected we kind of have to have
some notion of understanding that you
then you know either a or the
understanding it properly or B is this
one out of ten articles on that topic
and it's the only one that points in
that direction and the other nine
appointee in the opposite direction how
do we tell ya the the jury idea only
really fixes the click bait issue if
someone still has a very eloquent Lee
worded false information it'll still
spread well so it doesn't help with
actual resemblance to reality yeah I I
think it tackles an important thing but
I think with all of it if we just fix
one it's just going to get gained in a
slightly different way so it sort of
needs to be like multiple things
happening not necessarily at the same
time but like intent you know in tandem
ish so that at some point they're all
sort of touching and good going towards
the same goal which hopefully prevents
these individual things from being gay
yeah so have a secondary thing of kind
of fact-checking and validation of
experts which is very much in the wiki
election space and fact-checking which
is B reason score space which will get
dive into detail if anyone wants to so
for the moment what Adriel I'm gonna
invite a drill and Bentley to watch
instead of participate and then see what
everyone else comes up with in the
adjacent space and maybe I might might
also because I have my own ideas but I
didn't worked on them so I'm very
nebulous it's like I just want
information what do you think 10,000
people would want in a news source like
what is it that they get from news that
together we could solve like news to me
is information so it's like truth and
trust and so asking people how do you
know it's true and then how do you trust
something and then figuring out how to
make something with that involved in it
what could that look like with that
isn't a million dollars because all my
ideas really like I already said I need
the science and history one in place so
like that's already really those in
place to tackle this how can we just
tackle this with what's going on
what could we have
shut up so it's all on you guys
wiki Tribune has the clickbait thing and
the categories thing already it doesn't
have the juries we could buy ads for
wiki Tribune with a hundred thousand
dollar or ten thousand whatever we could
and send them where one more people to a
site that oh I see something pretty
close to I mean long as its own options
out there if we had a hundred thousand
dollars we can buy ads to help people
know about wiki Tribune just practical
what we could do
well Adriel a bit later on Butte is have
all of the people with sense making
projects that already exist
what's that point come together and
create one like closer and say although
right like what does yours offer how do
we sorry have a third party rate though
have a third party say here's why you're
here's why we would use from reasons for
or wiki what is it called wiki Tribune
social or wiki lecture on community like
a third like third party assess what
what these things look like or new
sources how can we enough people watch
the news I'm gonna have like five
different thoughts at once enough people
watch the news if we were able to say no
what's wrong and what works with like
what we're watching on network news and
have a conversation like conversation
about current events but like a
conversation and not a tweeting me
yelling at each other and having actual
is something we could do is gonna get us
be more informed no but it make fun one
of the problems is the 10,000 people
where do they come from I mean the
background and why no statistically mmm
if you get random 10,000 people the news
you are going to get a like about the
cut
chants and all the stuff that is totally
not relevant to anything I'm afraid and
if you are talking about ten thousand
people who are who would like to see
news that are relevant and maybe
something about science and about
technology and about serious stuff then
I guess the best use for ten thousand
Minds curation of the news from like
there's a source less trusted to get at
least the facts right and then ten
thousand pairs of eyes I guess the news
quite well and statistically in that ten
thousand Minds pool there would be at
least few experts at least people who
know about any field field enough to ask
right questions if someone comes up with
even very eloquently written article
which is follows someone in that ten
thousand people group would be able to
come up with sufficiently sharp
questions to you know poke the balloon
of the falsity of that article in that
article so yeah a few dollars as a
reward for finding Fox News maybe and
for rewarding good articles and for
rewarding curation process itself so not
a lot but still sucking that feels like
reward so that ten thousand is is
purposefully vague because he can be any
ten thousand you want it to be so we'd
like we could get ten thousand
journalists together and ask them write
your business is dying
yet what you do is so important what
could we create that gets people the
information gets you your needs met and
gets an information source and that
might be when it comes through right as
ten thousand journalists create a
platform to but they also need to
include that they have to include trust
and transparency and we might it's only
including design for them we're not
gonna pay for it right so it needs to be
balanced with is it is it worth it's
worth whatever the cost is how do you
finance journalism in a way that isn't
going to bias it yeah it might be
helpful to look at some of those micro
transaction models like if if they exist
could could you use tokens that are
cashed out you know once they hit a
certain limit so you're not getting
crushed by the transaction fees you know
and you have like community voting
essentially on articles and I mean I
don't know I'm just throwing ideas
around if we want to pay people you know
for doing really good stuff that doesn't
have the corporate and the backing of
things of entities that have agendas we
got to free up these folks to really do
what they're talented at a look Cheney
steam it steam it's called and it works
more or less like this exactly right you
can said it's not a new site it's not
the site is kind of blocking space maybe
something like this but the point is it
uses microtransactions and everyone is
able to vote on some articles they like
and voting is basically identical to
paying the author of the article so I'm
not sure how well it works I look at
that the years ago and you just start
I'm not sure if it how it works now so I
mean if the model is proven to be doing
a good thing or not but something like
this exists Shila do you have any I have
a couple things I don't know if they fit
in right here one thing I was thinking
is if we had like credentials of the
sort each person that puts out an
article then there's like a link to all
the articles they put out before and
where they've gone so you can kind of
get a framework of their stance and just
an easy way to click on that so you can
see their history in a way also I was
thinking a lot about right now we're
talking online and clicking but what
about radio I feel like radio is
actually possibly more harmful because
there's these short bursts of stories
they're just their take on a story often
and they're not actually they don't even
know the real source they don't really
know the background that they're giving
a lot of information to people who grab
it and think that now they have more
ammo to attack the other side whichever
radio station so just I was thinking is
there a way to would there be a way to I
don't know if I would say reprimand
people but having a way to say that's
that story that you heard a half-hour
ago
is false or most of us or something I
don't know mm-hmm
I don't know if there's a possibility
but it would be great be great to be
able to retract any kind of
misinformation that we put out into the
world it's painful is it a bad way Oh
retracted information oh there is
nothing called a soundbite which I
Tigers
equivalent to a meme in a written space
but in radio space it's soundbite and of
mr. president Trump who is tall - these
are good at sound bites and that's a
form of very actually that's a nasty way
of communicating because when you say
something that is catchy enough and it's
short enough you don't actually provide
any useful information in this thing but
still it spreads like wildfire he said
something really catchy and it puts some
something bad light and yeah this is
wrong this is such a rich space that's
why there's so many people working in it
and yet like what could ten thousand
people coming together and doing like
let's say ten thousand Vancouverites if
once clothes came together and said okay
we we clearly add spec kuva right it's
what local federal and global news what
is it we need what are the sectors and
what is there one we want to concentrate
on and start there or do we want like a
lot about a little or a little but a lot
right so um how deep do we want to go
and I think that is about working
through it with 10,000 people asking
like what is it you you trust in news um
one of the things I would like to see if
we're gonna have experts be on the news
is like a voting system for who are
those experts I know like the background
is great but also like okay you have an
economist it's actually an economist
it's the top of their field but how many
of the other economists agree with them
and how often have they been right which
I know is the background but like to be
able to actually say you know who I'd
like to have a conversation like Bernie
Sanders and Joe Rogan I know they
already have but like you don't it mean
that like we can vote that up and then
invite them and and it wouldn't be
mandatory we're not think of remember
not anything but like hey
people want you to talk and we want
these two experts to have a conversation
if there's going to be experts having
conversations and that's the news is I
think one powerful tool that could be
made with 10,000 people or like Mateus
said there's there are experts in that
10,000 so asking who it who are the
medical experts who are the technology
experts and asking why why are they
experts in can they actually stand
behind that like can they predict things
that fields they have unique thoughts in
that field today if something comes to
mind I think I saw something like this
not too long ago about for politicians
but what if you had like like a rotten
tomatoes or a rating system for
journalists and maybe the experts
themselves um I mean I'm on my laptop so
I think like what if I had a Chrome
browser extension that like could
automatically find the journalists name
in the article and then I could click
that and like people could either read
reviews or I could see a bunch of other
headlines they had ever written across
multiple sites I you know that comes to
mind that's something that could be
helpful you know maybe I don't know
enough about the browser but like could
a browser extension like automatically
it's the code right so could it
automatically put in a little rating
system next to their name you know and
the in the code and like you want this
browser extension because it's gonna
help you when you open that article it
will be so useful especially in my case
I I read quite a lot of like weird stuff
and weird stuff includes people quoting
so-called medical experts and I very
often get like oh this prove
that something works or something
doesn't because the doctor said is true
or it's not and when I google for the
name of the doctor yeah they have the
title but they also have a history of
very bad science of like being sued for
malpractice and stuff like that so being
able to immediately see all the history
of the other person not maybe not even
with writing but just raw history have
they had maybe been sued for something
history of their research and was the
research actually you know the comment
he agreed that the research is correct
and stuff like that it'll be very
helpful it Robert Lee do you want to
come back in it was only an invitation
like have to happen well I mean that
last a little bit I was thinking about
wiki lecture and a Joe's actually
because he has the expert sort of thing
and I don't know I drew if you'd
considered a plug-in but you definitely
Daniel that's definitely possible I've
actually written a couple plugins that
the manipulate the the webpage there's
something else I was gonna save
everybody yeah I think the plug-in is
almost mandatory at this point like it
kind of has to be a plugin so that you
can start to sort of interject this
information on you know maybe new
sources that wouldn't like that level of
transparency and I think things like you
know it could understand the webpage and
figure out who the author is if we have
a team of people going through and sort
of collecting information and submitting
it you can also just know like oh you're
at that you know web address on that
website you're reading this article
somebody's already you know crawled that
scraped it we've reviewed it here's the
outcome and then as well for things like
did videos and technically even audio
have something like you know if you have
a video playing on
you tube that's you know been identified
by this thing say oh you're playing this
video from the source we've reviewed it
and to change the player to add
something to it so it as you're watching
the video things get flighted like oh
that that's true you hear here's why now
oh that did this whole thing here it is
not true here's why now and this thing
it's not true or false he's just making
a claim with no evidence so yeah one of
the things when the toosh was talking
about the like debunked doctors and
stuff especially i actually want a
timeline on what happens there because
if they were credible up and to the
point they published something
controversial and now they've been
discredited what does that mean right so
like to have the actual timeline of
right they were sued for malpractice 30
times then decided to do this versus oh
they were really well established and
then they fell from grace and now we're
vilify them my god I know a doctor in
Australia who's been in a year-long
battle to have because they wanted to
revoke his medical license so that could
look bad but really it's because he's
bucking a misinformation trend in the
medical area that he's in and the
organisation's in charge of the medical
licenses are pretty biased so it depends
kind of on how you look at it it'd be
hard to to get a snapshot into that
although it'd be good to have the info
but this the timeline it's also no good
good I guess to like dream big as well
you know if you had this browser
extension or you know some kind of
platform that mixed in and I mean what
if you what if journalists could also
like make a profile on there and then
you could build in like a token system
I mean I'm look I'm the type of person
I'm probably pretty average I just read
the article I've no you know I don't
follow certain journalists or something
but my
if I liked something then I could see
more articles by them or I could send I
don't know I I'm still concerned about
the monetary aspect you know it would be
cool to be able to have an account and
like seven people tokens and once it hit
a certain amount it cashed out I don't
know if anyone knows could you merge
those that's just me
thinking big definitely got off topic
all the way it's very hard to stick with
10,000 people at $100,000 ballad
especially for this one that we
literally live in all the time so we're
near the end I just want to go around
and we can each say what we think is the
most powerful thing that we could create
with ten thousand people in a hundred
thousand dollars in this space right now
I might already know what he does and
that these are well actually I probably
wouldn't say recent score doesn't quite
fit in this space a lot of Adrian's
ideas probably well but I'd you know
after talking through I really liked the
idea of some sort of random chosen jury
to validate or to at least look and see
the value of content and include that
kind of retitling that wiki WT social
does and and I think you could do that
within that dollar amount and that that
space that might be something
interesting yeah I think if you combined
that with just like a simple system that
sort of help people group news articles
so you can say all these neuticle all of
these news articles are about the same
thing and then almost have the jury sort
of like try to create the the aggregate
the okay so with all this known what's
true what what should the headline be
that sort of thing and then I think you
can build that out in a lot of different
areas
you know for me I think the most
powerful thing we could do with a small
amount of money in people is to create
an imbd for politicians and business
leaders and journalists like just keep
adding to the list as we need them but
like the politicians specifically where
have they been wherever they were - did
they get their funding from and getting
that in a way then looking at what
because that's news in of itself right
how do we trust that where did we get
that from a lot of it's just public
discourse right well they learned the
CEO of this company that's public
information and having that either case
but having it done because if we did
that collectively it's not on one person
to then be legally liable for the you
know I mean it's like they're putting
out that person's information as opposed
to us collectively doing it'd be the
most powerful thing I think so that'll
be the IP ADB internet politicians
nativists the new name of food
collections of course so yeah that it
was actually considered oh I like that
and I like the fact of having it as a
time line if you can make it that way
we Kesey you like click on and then you
see that person's timeline like also I
like that idea when I come here I also
just end up feeling a bit inspired so I
guess I'm thinking today about you know
do I have friends locally that I already
know that like would want to get
together and just share the stuff that
matters to them you know on some
platform that exists just to get that
going in my own circle like that's what
I could probably do today so that's that
I love that Daniel okay so the point of
this is to bring inspirations like what
could we do with 10,000 people but like
bringing it down to the individual like
and there's things we can do today
without getting 10,000 people together
is also a very very even more powerful
thing so
we are at the 1 hour mark we can say
goodbye to YouTube and Facebook if
nobody has any closing questions all
right bye-bye